♪ Oh, Mr. Tailor ♪
["Mr. Tailor" playing]
♪ Holding the scissors ♪
♪ One cut, and it's settled ♪
[Atoy] You were my mother's best friend.
[Atoy] You deceived her before,
and now you're deceiving me every day
whenever you see my face.
How can you do that, Godmother?
Is my suspicion about you right?
I'm the product of their betrayal.
[Atoy] You're still making
a fool of me up to now!
[sobs]
[Atoy] Ibyang is the only one
who truly loves me!
She's the only genuine person in my life.
[Martina, in English] So, it's confirmed?
Sister Norma is still alive?
[Mongki, in English] Yes, ma'am.
My man confirmed it.
And he overheard that they're meeting
someone to talk to Atoy.
[in English] Hello, Sister Norma.
[in English] Remember me?
I was thinking of Master Grumpy.
If that happens, I'll probably leave him.
The child… Where is she?
[stammers] Ame is with Ibyang!
[Ame] I brought Ibyang with me.
She wanted to see Sister too.
[in English] Is something wrong, Martina?
[in English] I'm just really happy that
she's gonna meet her parents
for the first time.
[in English] I mean, you know me.
I love a family reunion story.
Doesn't seem like it.
Are you being fake with me?
It's crazy!
Our meeting place was so far,
and Sister Norma didn't even show up.
Now I can't contact them--
[Ame] Miss, why? Did something happen?
[Red] We need to get ahead of Atoy.
He must not know that Ibyang
is his daughter.
While you haven't met your parents yet,
can you…
PREVIOUSLY
Can you stay here again?
I'll think about it.
Are you still mad at me?
Just kidding!
[Ibyang] Me? Mad at you?
[music fades]
I'll take Red outside.
[in English] Just get the car.
[in English] Yes, ma'am.
Have you thought of a way?
How do we get Ibyang from Atoy?
We need to find someone who can pretend
to be Ibyang's real mother.
[suspicious music playing]
An actress?
[in English] Something like that, but…
she has to be on our side.
[music swells]
[music fades]
[suave theme music playing]
[gunshots]
[clacking]
[snipping]
[music swells]
[music fades]
Are you ready, children?
Yes!
Remember, watch and listen to our story.
In a faraway forest lived a poor princess!
She had a mother who was sick,
and one day, she found her mother at home!
Mom, I'm here!
- [pensive music playing]
- [gasps]
Mom?
- [kids giggling]
Mom!
Mom?!
Mom, wake up!
Wake up, Mom!
[children laugh]
Don't leave me!
We still have so many dreams.
You really left me for that?
[Martina, in English] Why? It-It's--
[in English] It's ridiculous.
- She's like crazy.
- Mom!
- [children laughing]
- [sobs]
Who did this to you, Mom?!
Mom, wake up, Mom.
[Charmi] The poor princess noticed
something strange!
There was a bite and two small marks
on her dead mother's neck!
Like a vampire's bite!
- [roars]
- [screams]
[roaring]
[children laughing]
[Olga] I know who did this.
Svetlana!
Face me!
I'm not afraid of you!
[deep breath]
Smoke, hurry.
And suddenly there was smoke!
[audience laughing]
Mars, hurry up.
Suddenly there's smoke, Mars.
And suddenly there was smoke!
- [inaudible]
- [grunts]
And suddenly there was smoke!
[imitates fizzing sound]
[sneaky music playing]
Then thunder and lightning,
and suddenly appeared…
Svetlana!
[cackling]
[audience laughing]
[Svetlana roars]
[Charmi] But the poor princess
did not surrender!
She was ready to fight!
[sneaky music playing]
I'm not afraid of you!
Prepare yourself!
[grunts]
- [imitates whooshing sound]
- [quirky stinging]
[audience laughing]
And Svetlana did not back down!
She wore her black cape
and unleashed her powerful… hair!
- [grunts]
- Then she screamed!
[screaming]
[grunting and groaning]
The poor princess's power was strong!
Svetlana was defeated in battle.
[quirky stinging]
Darkness ended, and goodness prevailed!
That woman might work for our plan.
[Martina, in English] What?
We need a serious actor for that.
[in English] Not some clown.
[in English] Look. Trust me on this.
She looks okay.
[Martina, in English] Okay.
[Charmi] And that's the end of our story!
[audience cheering, clapping]
[Charmi] Let's give her
a round of applause, children!
[audience cheering, clapping]
Tet, add 3K more!
Come on. What I did earlier was hard.
You saw it, right?
My gums hurt from those vampire fangs!
[Olga sighs] Unbelievable.
Sis, we're just a volunteer group,
and that's all the budget we have
for storytelling sessions.
Besides, a parent complained earlier.
Why was there a vampire killing a mother?
They said their child
might have nightmares.
And there's no vampire
with an aswang mother!
- Gosh!
- What's this?
So… exaggerated.
You know, they asked
for fantasy action drama, right?
If it's fantasy, anything goes!
Gosh, stop it, Tet!
[Tet] Just change it next time.
[Olga] Tet, add 3K to our talent fee.
If not, I'll tell your boss that
the receipts you're reimbursing
for volunteers' food are fake.
- [Tet] What?
- Oh, wow!
Oh, what?!
[in English] Girl… [scoffs]
Don't test me. I'll really do it.
I'm not a doctor, huh.
But I know the things you've been
"doctoring" for a long time.
- What, girl? What? Huh?
- [Charmi] Whoa! So that's how it is?
[Charmi] Yes, that's how it is.
Sis, you only need 3K.
That's 6K already!
Oh, why? Touch-move!
Stop complaining.
[Olga] Fine.
- Wait, I need to answer this.
- [phone rings]
- This Tet.
- See?
- That's how it works.
- Just a little push--
- Oh, there.
- It's 8K now.
Nice.
We have money for food now, right?
[in English] Hi, there.
[in English] I saw your acting earlier.
- Oh.
- [in English] You're very good.
Oh, not really.
- [roars]
- [Martina chuckles]
- [Martina, in English] Exactly.
- [in English] Thank you!
[in English] Can I have
your contact details?
[in English] I might have
an acting gig for you.
[in English] Yes, ma-- Yes, ma'am.
I have a set card here.
I'll send it to you.
Oh, just give me your number.
- Here.
- [in English] Thank you.
Here's my calling card.
[in English] Thank you!
[in English] Um, I'll call you later?
[in English] You think that maybe you'll…
you'll be free to meet us?
Yes, ma'am! I'll cancel
my pedicure for you.
- [in English] You can also, um…
- [in English] Yes, ma'am.
- bring your friend.
- Hmm. [in English] Thank you, ma'am!
[in English] Thank you.
[in English] Thank you, ma'am!
- [in English] See you later.
- [in English] Thank you.
[exclaiming]
- [pleasant music playing]
- [both scream]
We're amazing!
[exclaiming]
Amazing!
- Really!
- [exclaims]
You know, wait.
Could she be
a Hollywood producer?
Oh, shucks.
[in English] Oh my God. Oh my God!
Meryl Streep.
Girl, get ready because…
Olga Bonifacio is here.
[exclaiming]
[Charmi] It hurts, friend.
Hey, really!
We're so lucky!
[music fades]
[Martina clears throat]
[in English] Good afternoon.
[in English] I'm Olga Bonifacio.
[in English] Olga, for short.
[in English] Hello, judges.
[in English] I am Charmielyn Sanchez.
[in English] Charmi, for short.
Olga, I'll give you a scene.
I just want to see how you'll act it out.
G, Director!
[in English] Game, um…
What kind of scene do you want?
Um, let's say you gave up
your child for adoption,
then after a long time you meet again,
and you want to reunite.
How will you talk to her?
How will you introduce yourself?
Show us.
I'll just internalize, Director.
Wait. Wait, wait.
[suspicious music playing]
[sighs]
Do you want me to cry, Director?
Which side do you want?
Oh, do you want me to be doing something?
Like sweeping…
Just do it.
[Red] What?
[rousing music playing]
[melodramatic music playing]
My child!
[sobs]
My child…
It's me.
It's me, your mama.
[sobs]
I missed you so much.
[sobbing]
Forgive me.
Please forgive me for giving you up.
I didn't want to.
But I want to make it up to you.
I want to make it up to you
if you'll let me.
[music fades]
[in English] Cut.
- How was it?
- [mid-tempo rock music playing]
Send the other one home.
[in English] What do you mean?
[in English] We need her.
Olga can't just show up suddenly.
[in English] She needs to be endorsed.
[music fades]
How?
Sister Norma's niece already called Ame.
[in English] We just need
to follow through with that.
We need somebody to play Faye,
Sister Norma's niece.
[in English] Got it?
[in English] Yes.
- [mid-tempo rock music playing]
- [inaudible]
‪[music concludes]
[muffled chattering in the distance]
Ame, take care of Atoy, okay?
Sometimes he doesn't eat properly.
Don't worry, Miss Cita.
I'll find a way for you
and Atoy to talk again,
so you can go back to how you were before.
That might not happen anymore.
He sees me differently now.
And don't force it.
What's important is he's not alone.
He has you and Ibyang.
It's just sad what happened to you.
You've become like a mother to him.
[melancholic music playing]
[phone ringing]
Hello?
[Charmi] Ms. Ame!
[suspicious music playing]
Faye?
Oh, sorry!
I wasn't able to meet you last time
at the hospital.
Something happened to Sister Norma.
She had to go to the province.
But she left instructions!
Why does your voice sound different?
Ah, it's because, um3
[clears throat] I was sick--
[coughing]
[in English] Sorry.
I was sick then,
so maybe my voice sounded different.
Um…
Um, Ms. Ame, where can we meet Ibyang?
So we can bring her mother to you.
Huh?
You'll bring her later?
What's her name?
Olga Bonifacio.
Okay, Ms. Ame.
Let's just chat.
[in English] See you!
[music swells]
- You're good too, Charmi.
- Yes.
So later, you'll tag team with Olga.
- She's the mother, and you're…?
- Faye!
Sister Norma's niece.
Right? I memorized the profile
you gave me.
[in English] Good!
- [in English] Thank you.
- [chuckles]
[rousing music playing]
Hey, Ibyang.
Did you tidy your room?
Make sure, okay.
Change the bed sheets too!
Don't come down if it's not neat!
[Ibyang] Okay, Tatoy!
[phone ringing]
Yes, Sir Mike?
Yes, Sir Mike.
Uh, the suit you ordered is ready.
You can pick it up anytime.
[in English] Okay, thank you.
[mid-tempo rock music playing]
[Olga] Is this right?
- [music fades]
- [mutters]
[Faye] Is the child here now?
[Charmi] Eh…
That's what Ame said in her text.
[in English] Delfin's Tailoring Shop.
There it is.
Hmm, you know…
This place looks familiar.
[sneaky music playing]
I borrowed a suit here before!
Oh no.
Could it be…
Oh. Why are you smiling like that?
[clicks tongue]
Hey!
Don't think about that now!
Let's focus here!
We can't mess this up.
- We need to do great.
- Yes.
Honestly, I'm nervous
about this acting gig.
Because why won't they explain
why you need to get the child?
Never mind.
We're getting paid.
It's a big amount too!
If not for this gig,
we'd have nothing now, right?
[Olga] Did we pass?
Are we accepted?
[in English] Yes? Yes?!
[whooping, exclaiming]
[playful music playing]
- I told you, right?
- Told you, yes!
- [giggles]
- [whoops]
I'm amazing!
[Olga, in English] I'm so proud of myself.
[sighs] What is this?
When does the taping start?
I-Indie? Indie film?
[gasps]
[in English] Broadway!
[Martina, in English] Can you just…
shut it for just a minute?
[in English] Sorry.
[Martina, in English]
This is not an ordinary role.
[in English] You have to be
extremely convincing.
[in English] Improvisation skills
are a must.
Also, this will take a lot of your time.
[in English] So, listen very,
very carefully. Okay?
[in English] Okay. Um…
If ever, how much is my talent fee here?
[in English] For you, 200,000 a month.
[Martina] Plus miscellaneous expenses.
[in English] Okay?
[in English] This is
an indefinite contract.
We'll decide when to terminate
your services.
[in English] Your friend here
will get 50,000
for playing a supporting role.
[in English] One-time.
[in English] Okay! Game, game.
What do I need to do?
[sighs]
[music fades]
She's Ibyang.
You'll pretend to be her mother,
take her in.
You'll keep her in your care,
treat her like your real child.
We'll tell you when to stop pretending.
Ah, like reality TV?
[Charmi] Hmm. Mm-hmm.
Exactly, but…
no TV, no cameras watching you.
[in English] This is real life.
This is a real kid.
Only you are fake.
Only you are pretending.
[in English] Don't worry.
We'll supply ou with all the information
and background that you need.
There are just some people
that you need to watch out for
who might suspect you.
[in English] That's it.
Can we start from the top?
[sneaky music playing]
Oh, just kidding.
Just a joke.
[chuckles]
- Okay. Come on.
- [in English] Oh, game.
Let's change clothes. Where's my costume?
Here. Let's get ready.
[in English] Okay. Okay.
[in English] Olga Bonifacio. Listen to me.
You love Ibyang.
You're her mother, okay?
You love her because you need money.
[in English] Okay?
- [in English] Let's do it.
- [in English] Okay.
Oh, give it to me.
It's there, on the side.
Here, put on your shoes first.
Give me the shoes.
[blabbering]
[in English] One Mississippi.
[sharp exhale]
[Olga] Hey.
Just put it there.
Hello?
Good day!
[Atoy] What is it? You're here to have
something tailored?
Yes. I'd like a women's suit made.
[Atoy] Ah, okay. Just a moment.
I'm finishing something.
Just relax first.
[sneaky music playing]
Oh.
There's a child here?
[Atoy] Child?
Yes, my assistant.
[Olga] Ivy Santos.
[Atoy] Do you know Ibyang?
Ah, I just saw it on her ID.
- [Atoy] Mm-hmm.
- Where is she?
[Atoy] I thought you came for tailoring?
Why are you looking for her?
[suspicious music playing]
Yes, I'm here for tailoring.
You're so grumpy.
I was just curious
about your assistant, wow.
- [sighs]
- [Atoy] Just a moment.
I'm finishing something here.
[gasps, then squeals]
[Charmi] Hey, oh--
- Did Red send you?
- [gasping]
Huh? Who sent you?
- Help! Hey!
- [shrieking]
- [gasps, grunts]
- Hmm?
[grunting and groaning]
Ms. Ame, help Olga!
- Olga?
- [Olga] Atoy!
Oh, Atoy!
She's Ibyang's mother!
[rousing music playing]
‪[clicks tongue]
You're an animal, Atoy.
[mysterious music playing]
I already spoke to Olga's friend.
They're with Atoy now.
[suspicious music playing]
What?
So, you're Ibyang's mother?
- Ame, what's this?
- [sighs]
What?
Why are you only showing up now?
[in English] Sorry! Okay?
I just found out she's here!
I've been searching for so long!
Because you left her!
[sneaky music playing]
Ah, wait. Wait a minute.
What's going on?
[in English] Uh, excuse me.
I'm Faye, Sister Norma's niece.
She already went back to the province.
But she's happy
I brought Ibyang's mother here.
Atoy, she is the one I told you
we were supposed to meet
yesterday with Ibyang.
Her?
Wait.
How did you meet?
[whimsical music playing]
How did you meet?!
[sneaky music playing]
Brother, one please. The 20-peso one.
‪[indistinct chattering]
Henry!
- Oh, here's the money I owe you.
- [in English] Thank you.
[in English] Thank you!
I'll pay the rest later, okay?
- Uh, brother.
- Hmm?
I just want to ask.
Is the church with the image
of San Antonio de Padua nearby?
[Nestor] Ah, yes. It's close…
Second corner, turn right.
- Here, straight, then right?
- Right, straight ahead.
Why? Did you lose something?
Eh…
Well, my love life
has been missing for a long time.
I haven't had a boyfriend
in ages, brother.
Mm-hmm. So, I'll just leave it to prayers.
[both chuckling]
So, what are you looking for
in a man? Maybe…
Maybe our patron will have
a hard time with what you want.
- Oh no! It's simple.
- [laughs]
Simple.
Of course, handsome.
- That's important, right?
- [Nestor] Correct.
- Tall. Dresses well.
- [quirky sting]
You know, even if he's not rich,
that's fine with me.
- And I like someone who looks grumpy
- [chuckles]
but is kind in real life!
[both chuckling]
That's simple indeed.
- [quirky sting]
- [chuckles]
Uh, my advice to you…
Pray, and it will come.
- [in English] Prayers.
- Thanks.
Thank you. Drink that. It's good.
- [in English] Thank you!
- Henry, later, okay!
[gasps]
- Oh, what's that?!
- [Atoy, in English] Oh, sorry.
- [in English] Sorry. Sorry.
- What's that?
[romantic music playing]
[Atoy] Sorry. Sorry, sorry.
[chuckles softly]
Sorry, because--
It splashed.
- [in English] Sorry.
- [in English] Thank you.
- [chuckles softly]
- [in English] Sorry.
[in English] Oh my God!
[in English] San Antonio de Padua,
thank you.
You're so fast!
What's your name?
Ah, Atoy.
- Yes.
- [giggles]
Atoy, do you have a girlfriend?
- None, none.
- None, ah.
Well, if you're looking, um…
Here, call me at this number.
- [titters]
- [Atoy] Oh, okay--
If I get a boyfriend,
I'll make myself available for you, okay?
Wow, jeez.
You're too fast, miss.
Don't you want us
to get to know each other first?
What do you want to know?
Uh…
[music fades]
[electronic blipping]
She's Olga. She's your mother.
[lively theme music playing]
What about Brother Atoy?
[T-Bak] Then he'll just go solo in life?
There's still Sis…
Ame and Miss Cita.
Oh, but Cita's gone!
She resigned!
Why is your mother
not there anymore, Karla?
I know that you'll be happier there,
that your identity will be complete.
I'll miss you.
Eventually, the child
has to be disposed of.
What do you mean, disposed of?
She can be included in a shipment or…
get rid of her, so there's no trace.
[Emerson] 'Toy, I just want to know.
Has the DNA test result
been emailed to you?
It's being sent now.
UP NEXT
Yes, it's here.
["Mr. Tailor" playing]
♪ Fix it ♪
Subtitle translation by: Rachel C. Arias